thursdayboots.com 2019-02-23

# Privacy Statement

## Section 1 - What Information Do We Collect?

When you purchase something from our store, as part of the buying and selling process, we collect the personal information you give us such as your name, address, and email address.

When you browse our store, we automatically collect certain information about your device, such as details regarding your web browser, IP address, and time zone. We also collect information about the page(s) you visit, actions you take on the site (e.g., completing a purchase), or how you arrived at our site (e.g., search, paid advertisement).

To track and store this information, we use the following technologies/services:

  * **Cookies**. Cookies are small files stored in browsers which are used to save user preferences.
  * **Google Analytics**. To gather information about how customers shop in our store, we use Google Analytics, a service provided by Google. You can view more information on this service here. We also use Google Signals, which allows Google Analytics to associate data from your visit to our site with other Google information. Remember, all of your Google data may be accessed and/or deleted by you via [My Activity](https://myactivity.google.com/myactivity).

Additionally, when you begin or complete a purchase through our website, we collect certain information from you, including your name, email, billing/shipping address, and payment information.

Collectively, all types of information gathered or provided to us by you as "Personal Information."

## Section 2 - How Do We Use Your Information?

When you provide Personal Information as part of a transaction, we use the order information to fulfill any orders placed through our website. This includes processing payment, shipping item(s), and sending order information/confirmations. We may also use it to communicate with you regarding your order, screen orders for potential fraud, or provide advertising for additional products/services.

Other information collected as you browse the site, including page(s) visited, actions taken, or referral source, may be used to personalize your browsing experience, assess website performance, or for marketing/advertising purposes. With your permission, we may also send you emails about our store, new products, and other updates.

## Section 3 - How Do You Get My Consent?

When you provide us with personal information to complete a transaction, verify your credit card, place an order, arrange for a delivery or return a purchase, we imply that you consent to our collecting it and using it for that specific reason only.

If we ask for your personal information for a secondary reason (e.g., marketing), we will either ask you directly for your expressed consent or provide you with an opportunity to say no.

## Section 4 - How Do I Withdraw My Consent?

If, after you opt-in, you change your mind, you may withdraw your consent for us to contact you, for the continued collection, use or disclosure of your information, at anytime, by contacting us at [founders@thursdayboots.com](mailto:founders@thursdayboots.com) or mailing us at: 48 W 21st St., 6th Floor, New York, NY, 10010, United States.

If you wish to delete or block cookies from your browsing activity, you may do so within your browser.

If you wish to opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics, you may do so [here](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

## Section 5 - Disclosure

We may disclose your personal information if we are required by law to do so or if you violate our Terms of Service.

## Section 6 - Shopify

Our store is hosted on Shopify Inc. They provide us with the online e-commerce platform that allows us to sell our products and services to you.

Your data is stored through Shopify’s data storage, databases and the general Shopify application. They store your data on a secure server behind a firewall.

Payment:

If you choose a direct payment gateway to complete your purchase, then Shopify stores your credit card data. It is encrypted through the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI-DSS). Your purchase transaction data is stored only as long as is necessary to complete your purchase transaction. After that is complete, your purchase transaction information is deleted.

All direct payment gateways adhere to the standards set by PCI-DSS as managed by the PCI Security Standards Council, which is a joint effort of brands like Visa, MasterCard, American Express and Discover.

PCI-DSS requirements help ensure the secure handling of credit card information by our store and its service providers.

For more insight, you may also want to read Shopify’s Terms of Service [here](https://www.shopify.com/legal/terms) or Privacy Statement [here](https://www.shopify.com/legal/privacy).

## Section 7 - Third-Party Services

In general, the third-party providers and brand partners used by us will only collect, use and disclose your information to the extent necessary to allow them to perform the services they provide to us and/or market products and services that may be of interest to you.

However, certain third-party service providers, such as payment gateways and other payment transaction processors, have their own privacy policies in respect to the information we are required to provide to them for your purchase-related transactions.

For these providers, we recommend that you read their privacy policies so you can understand the manner in which your personal information will be handled by these providers.

In particular, remember that certain providers may be located in or have facilities that are located in a different jurisdiction than either you or us. So if you elect to proceed with a transaction that involves the services of a third-party service provider, then your information may become subject to the laws of the jurisdiction(s) in which that service provider or its facilities are located.

As an example, if you are located in Canada and your transaction is processed by a payment gateway located in the United States, then your personal information used in completing that transaction may be subject to disclosure under United States legislation, including the Patriot Act.

Once you leave our store’s website or are redirected to a third-party website or application, you are no longer governed by this Privacy Policy or our website’s Terms of Service.

Links

When you click on links on our store, they may direct you away from our site. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites and encourage you to read their privacy statements.

## Section 8 - Security

To protect your personal information, we take reasonable precautions and follow industry best practices to make sure it is not inappropriately lost, misused, accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed.

If you provide us with your credit card information, the information is encrypted using secure socket layer technology (SSL) and stored with a AES-256 encryption. Although no method of transmission over the Internet or electronic storage is 100% secure, we follow all PCI-DSS requirements and implement additional generally accepted industry standards.

Cookies

Here is a partial list of cookies that we use. We’ve listed them here so you can choose if you want to opt-out of cookies or not.

_session_id, unique token, sessional, Allows Shopify to store information about your session (referrer, landing page, etc).

_shopify_visit, no data held, Persistent for 30 minutes from the last visit, Used by our website provider’s internal stats tracker to record the number of visits

_shopify_uniq, no data held, expires midnight (relative to the visitor) of the next day, Counts the number of visits to a store by a single customer.

cart, unique token, persistent for 2 weeks, Stores information about the contents of your cart.

_secure_session_id, unique token, sessional

storefront_digest, unique token, indefinite If the shop has a password, this is used to determine if the current visitor has access.

## Section 9 - Retention

We retain Personal Information we receive as described in this policy for as long as you use our services or as long as is necessary to fulfill the purpose(s) for which it was collected.

When you place an order through the Site, we will store your order Information unless and until you ask us to delete this information.

## Section 10 - Right of Access

If you are a European resident, you have the right to access any personal information we have collected from you. You also have the right to ask that your personal information be corrected, updated, or deleted. To exercise this right, please contact us at [founders@thursdayboots.com](mailto:founders@thursdayboots.com) or via mail at 48 W 21st St., 6th Floor, New York, NY, 10010, United States.

Also, if you are a European resident and have provided personal information to us for marketing, browsing, or transactional reasons, please note that your information will be transferred outside of Europe, including to Canada and the United States.

## Section 11 - Age of Consent

By using this site, you represent that you are at least the age of majority in your state or province of residence, or that you are the age of majority in your state or province of residence and you have given us your consent to allow any of your minor dependents to use this site.

## Section 12 - Changes to Policy

We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently. Changes and clarifications will take effect immediately upon their posting on the website. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here that it has been updated, so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we use and/or disclose it.

If our store is acquired or merged with another company, your information may be transferred to the new owners so that we may continue to sell products to you.

## Questions and Contact Information

If you would like to: access, correct, amend or delete any personal information we have about you, register a complaint, or simply want more information contact our Privacy Compliance Officer at [founders@thursdayboots.com](mailto:founders@thursdayboots.com) or by mail at

Thursday Boot Company

Re: Privacy Compliance Officer

48 W 21st St., 6th Floor

New York, NY, 10010, United States
